hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast if this is your
first time listening my name is jeremiah
krakowski and i help coaches and
trainers grow their businesses to seven
and eight figures
but even if you're not making that much
money yet or wanting to make that much
money and it sounds like it's too much i
help people go from zero to making six
figures
all the way up the chain and so if you
need help
growing your business as a coach or
trainer i show you how to get more
clients and make more money and i've
been doing it for 19 years i've been
helping coaches and trainers scale their
businesses to tens of millions of
dollars
this podcast is all about that using
online direct response marketing and
social media to do so now today
we're going to talk about what to say in
your social media videos the truth is
video is the number one format right now
on social media on the internet in
general and it's only going to become
more so
i have a course on my website called
social media content creation
made easy you can find it over at
jeremiahkowski.com under courses social
media content creation made easy
uh and it's a definitive course as to
like what you should say you also get a
whole archive of my courses
not courses um
a whole archive of my social media posts
that's what it is by the way i don't i
don't edit this podcast i just
click record and let it go and that's
part of my methodology is my friends you
shouldn't worry about making mistakes
as part of life
if you're a coach if you're a trainer
and you're worried about saying
everything perfect and sounding perfect
and saying all the right things
all the time you're gonna lose it you're
gonna lose out and you're gonna go nuts
and you're not gonna make any money as a
coach or trainer okay
so give yourself some grace and that's
one of the number one things when it
comes to making video
on social media one of the first lessons
i tell people
don't worry about it being perfect don't
worry about it getting the perfect
result i've worked with dozens of people
where they literally will will
not post on social media unless it's
perfect
for whatever reason
in working with them i honestly think
that they need to
possibly go to therapy for that
that it may have to do with mental
health
reason why
they
struggle to even
communicate like a normal person on
video okay and if that's you it's no
shame in that there's a lot of great
resources out there find somebody to
talk to usually the reason why we're
afraid is something inside of us some
kind of belief something is telling us
that bad horrible painful things will
happen if we don't do everything perfect
okay so that's really like the
foundation when it comes to i know i
just dove right in there on the deep end
with you on this but that's one of the
biggest things my friends is you have to
get past whatever that is inside your
brain
that's telling you that you got to be
perfect
on social media to make videos
that you got to look perfect that you
gotta sound perfect that you gotta say
all the perfect words
okay
i get it we've had people tell us stuff
our whole life
especially i have a lot of women that
follow me
it's a i think it's a thousand times
harder for for women but i know that i
know that i know that you can't let that
stop you from impacting people and if
you're a coach if you're a trainer and
you've got something inside of you and
you and you want to help people and you
want to impact them with your content
you can't let
that stop you you can't let how you feel
stop you from reaching people
from building the business that you want
to want to build
people that i know that are successful
at making content and using it and
growing a platform some of you know my
mom
she's got millions of people on her
social media another one of my clients
rick pino listen
perfection is the last thing they think
about when they post on social media
that's the number and it's the number
one thing that i see that stops people
is just worrying about it being perfect
now if that's not your worry
and you're like that's not my worry i'm
okay with it it doesn't need to be
perfect
imperfect action is what it takes but
you just don't know what to say
that's what this episode is for us what
should we say in our videos how should
we make
video content
and it's kind of again tied to a little
bit of that
but it's a common thing most people are
like what should i say i'm gonna answer
that question for you
in in
as few words as possible and as simply
as possible
your content can be anything related to
what your target customer
cares about
now who is your target customer
well
you find that out by answering there's a
few simple questions you can answer and
i actually
have now it's called a recipe for
jasper.ai we use jasper.ai to come up
with all of our copy and even a lot of
our social media content and it's based
off of
it's based off of
these questions right here so you answer
who is your customer
what problem do they have what solution
do you offer them
what does your methodology the way that
you deliver that result help what's the
best case scenario like your top point
five percent of dream customers the
dream result
that they would want
what keeps them up at night what are
they afraid of what are their top three
daily frustrations
what are their built-in biases and what
do they secretly desire that they won't
tell anybody else about when it relates
to success
and their ultimate goals and anything
else related to their personality and
this actually uh comes from my years of
experience but there's actually a book
that i would highly recommend for you
called the ultimate sales letter i know
we're talking about social media content
the ultimate sales letter by dan kennedy
is a really it's a it's an easy read
book
uh
about
this topic and the very first chapter is
specifically about
what to do before writing your sales
letter you got to start with
reverse engineering who your customer is
okay
so you have to figure out you got to get
into the mind of the customer it's
actually chapter yeah chapter one
and i answer these questions the market
diagnosis profiling questions
and
once you know that
you kind of have this profile of who
is the most likely person to buy from
you you know so it could be women that
are in menopause that want to feel sexy
and not afraid to be themselves and and
live the life of their dreams maybe lose
10 pounds
without sacrificing their career working
hours in the gym or
or
cooking food all day long or starving
themselves okay like that's one of my
clients examples right
but
you don't want to make all of your
content to be about
that thing that you do and this is where
it gets really fun
you want your content related to
not what you do
but
who the person is
who is that person everything starts
with who first
all your products your offers the way
you sell
and your social media content and what
to say on videos
and so when you're making video content
now
almost all of our video content that
we're making is
i'm either doing a podcast like this
about 20 to 30 minutes long where i'm
actually doing the whole teaching i'll
have a recorded course
or i'll do a a boot camp of some kind
that's maybe a couple hours long so
that's long form video content and
that's that's a little bit easier
because you figure out the exact goal
and you break it down step by step you
take time to break it down
that's actually
not that difficult to do
especially when you have some notes to
go off of the hard part is how do you
take all of that information and
condense it down to reach your target
customer so social media is one of the
best ways to reach your target customer
instagram and tick tock
okay
so if you go over to my instagram right
here you can see i have these short
videos that i do on my instagram
all of them are under a minute long and
over on my tick tock i got the same
thing going on
okay so i got these short videos
where i'm speaking to
my target customer
and stuff that relates to them the a
that i want them to know
that i want them to learn
that's going to help them that's going
to help them reach their goals but most
of my videos here's the here's the big
part
most of my videos have nothing to do
with what i'm actually selling
they have everything to do with
who my target customer is a coach or a
trainer that wants to get more customers
make more money in their business and so
that's who i think about and all of my
content is based around what does that
person care about the most
okay
so if you are a coach or trainer
or even if you're watching this and
you're not you're in e-commerce or
you're in you have an agency
think about your customer who gives you
their money
what do they care about
what are they dealing with in life
what is preventing them from making the
decision to take action with you
what is stopping them from reaching
their goals
this is where a lot of especially
coaches and trainers miss it because
they're like well if i gave all that
away i'd have nothing to sell
you gotta
flip
your thinking like i just flipped my hat
you gotta flip your thinking on this
you want to give away your best content
for free
and i hear people they tell me well but
i spent years learning that why would i
give away what cost me millions to learn
my friends if you want to be successful
as a coach or trainer
this is how you do it
and for the last 19 years this is what
we've taught people to do this is what
has helped this is what has worked and
it produces the most profitable
financial results
so you can choose to stay broke and not
do this out of your own pride and ego
i probably lost some listeners on that
one
they'll stay broke
or
you can decide
to give your best content for free
and you
lay it all out there on social media
including the stuff you charge for
now you might say people would say well
then what do i have to charge for
the same stuff
all the stuff that's in my paid courses
is also on my social media
is also in my podcast
but it's not organized in the same way
it's not put into a specific format
most of the people on my social media
don't get a lot of results off the
social media
does that mean that i'm a failure no it
doesn't
my social media see the goal of your
social media videos is to attract who
your target customer is
to draw them in
so then you can promote to them your
offers that you have for sale
and then you sell them something
and so what's the fastest best way to
attract the person who's actually going
to buy what you sell by giving them the
thing that they want the most
on your social media
in bite-sized chunks
and so
you might say well i don't know what
that is that they want well then you
haven't worked with enough people
i'm just being real
if you work with enough clients if you
talk with enough people you'll know
exactly what they want
i didn't know what customers wanted i
knew what i thought they
cared about and what i had some skill
set in in the beginning but it wasn't
until i started working with
thousands
of coaches and trainers
and now i'm like i know exactly what
they want i know exactly what they need
to do and i know exactly how to lead
them there
and so some of y'all just need to get
more at bats under you start working
with some people
start connecting with some people start
building a a clientele
and start talking to those people more
and more
and they will literally tell you what
they want and then all you do is on your
content you literally give them what
they asked you for
you literally give them the solution to
the problem that they asked you about
i did this uh
this podcast episode right here came out
of a coaching call that i did
i pulled my audience it was the second
most desired
podcast episode this month that they
wanted me to do
so i'm recording
it i didn't have to think
you know i've had a lot of people they
actually get offended by that they're
like wow you took our conversation and
turned it into a piece of content
well yeah i didn't say your name you're
like what yeah but like i thought that
was our private conversation i'm sorry
my
my friends like
if you're in
the industry and we connect i'm going to
use all of our conversations as content
some some people have a mental stigma
against doing that for what i'm not sure
why
um i'm not identifying anybody's
personal information when i do that
but
for whatever it is maybe they want
credit maybe i don't know again that's a
that's an ego issue
that's a
kind of a pride issue
um
i don't know
and that's that's the third part that
i'm gonna get to listen if you're gonna
be successful as a coach or trainer
you're gonna piss people off
you're gonna upset people you're going
to make them
there's going to be a whole segment of
people that just don't like how you do
things you rub them wrong you make them
feel bad
just by being you
by me talking right now
i make a segment of the market of
coaches and trainers
not feel very comfortable
and i'm not afraid of that
i want to work with the ones that love
what i'm talking about because there's a
whole segment of people like they're
like you guys are loving what i'm saying
right now too
because i'm shooting straight
and that's who i work with
that's who becomes my customer
that's who becomes my client
okay
and so what you do is when you make
content when you make these videos again
instagram
and tick tock is where it's at with
video
i do facebook videos a lot less than we
used to
you can get organic followers this is
all organic in this last like probably
six months
because now i can go live on here
and i can run ads through tick tock i
have an upcoming course all about that
that i'm just now finishing up buttoning
up the final lessons on
for tick tock ads on how to reach people
that are course creators and coaches
through tick tock with my courses with
my trainings
and so
what content should you put on your
videos it's anything that's that will
attract
when if you got somebody that is your
target customer they're scrolling
through your social media
and they see your video and they're like
oh wow they're speaking exactly to me
about the exact thing that i care about
that's what you make your content about
now not
about 20 of the time i go outside of
that like this right here
metaverse right i'm really passionate
about the metaverse
i think that all course creators and
trainers are going to have to operate in
the metaverse in the next 10 to 15 years
so that's that's a big reason why i seed
it into my content because i think it's
going to be a huge part of our everyday
life
and web 3.0 but right now it's not but i
seed some of that into my content
because i think it's a very valuable
part of that
and so it doesn't it's not like i have
nothing to sell related to the metaverse
i have nothing to sell related to
copywriting i have nothing to sell
related to
prospects pain points maybe i do with my
offer course
most of what i talk about isn't related
to what i'm actually selling
at all
but it's the exact lessons that my
target customer needs
to reach their goals
so step out there
stop being afraid to give away your best
content for free
stop gatekeeping and holding back your
best content
and start sharing it on social media and
you're going to be surprised
how well it does
now if you're hearing me say this and
you're still like but you didn't tell me
what to say
okay
here goes
make a list of topics
that your target customer cares about
three topics
i'm sure you can come up with that right
like
if you can't again you need to work with
more customers
three topics
make a short video
with a hook
related to
what those customers care about and tell
a story
one of the best things to do is to
personalize it
you know i used to struggle to get sales
online
when i finally learned about how to
strategically talk to my target customer
how to confidently make videos
i was able to make the best content that
gets the most engagement
so that's a video that you could post
now that's kind of generic you want to
get very specific about that when i
learned exactly how to speak to the
niche of customer our sales went up by
300 percent when i started talking to
not just online business owners
but coaches
okay now here's another way that i could
do that you know
i was marketing to coaches but i was
actually losing money by advertising
without talk talking to the exact
customer that i wanted i realized i
needed to mention that i work with
people with social media based marketing
because i don't do anything that's not
related to social media and the internet
see so by getting specific about that
and telling my story and documenting my
story
in that i'm able to share from my
perspective
what i learned
which is a lesson
that my customer can use now here's
something really cool
in jasper again jasper ai
i recommend this to everybody
and you can get a free free trial of it
there's actually a way that you can
generate a script
like this
okay
so i'm gonna show you for your videos
how to use jasper to generate a script
so i have a recipe right here
um it's basically a three-step
it's a three-part recipe
it's really simple
i might add a third part
write a
video
script
based on the above
there okay so if we do this let's just
put um women who are struggling
to
find
friends
[Music]
who support them
who are
single and
[Music]
child free
they need help
[Music]
learning to connect
feel like they don't have
people who support them okay there's
another client of mine kind of kind of
similar topic so we're going to have
jasper
write a pas problem agitate solution it
can be hard to find friends who support
it especially if you're a single woman
who doesn't have kids you can feel like
you're alone in your struggles and don't
have anyone to connect with we've
created a safe place for women to
connect with
come join our community okay now write a
paragraph based on the above it can be
difficult to find that
okay
i'm actually going to add this right
here
write a creative story
in the first person
based on the above
i was feeling alone i had just moved to
a new city and didn't have any friends i
was struggling to find people that
supported me especially since i was
single and didn't have kids i felt like
i was alone in my struggles okay
generate a list of youtube video titles
finding friends who support you
single and child free women's group
connecting with others who understand
write a video script based on the above
hi and i'm a single woman who doesn't
have kids it can be hard to find friends
who support you especially if you're
like me and don't have kids that's why i
want to tell you about a group that i
actually found we're all connecting
together and supporting each other we
laugh we cry we share so like these
gives you ideas for scripts that you can
use and jasper generated all of that
right there okay so you can use jasper
to come up with what you actually say
with your content just by typing in
those questions right there and you can
use
this to learn how to do that
actually going to copy this right here
into the recipe i've still been working
on the recipe that's why i haven't
released it fully
um
there we
go yeah that's the recipe
it'll help you generate some really
great
social media content ideas
right there i'll try to include a link
to it on my
podcast and my website
jeremiahkowski.com
i'll link to that recipe because i think
that that's a really good one
okay you go to jeremiahkowski.com
forward slash podcast you can find all
the show notes and the links right there
okay
so when it comes to like what you should
say in your content
how you should make video content it's
all about learning how to tell your
story in a way that connects with who
your target customer is
and so you draw people in by
personalizing it and sharing the outcome
the result that you got and that you
learned
and then you put that on your videos now
the more you do that you're going to
find certain videos pop
certain videos get
more engagement
and so when you notice certain videos
are getting more engagement here's a
like
the easiest thing in the book that you
can do
you just make more videos like the one
that got a lot of engagement
around that specific thing and you make
less videos about the topics that got
less engagement
because they relate to who your target
customer is
so like i find topics like boundaries
and
learning how to
say no and not people please are huge
because coaches and trainers if they
want to build a business successfully
got to break past
people-pleasing and learn how to set
healthy boundaries because it's going to
make their lives
better and they're going to be more
successful
in the process
okay
and that's how i've gotten a lot of my
videos you know about six months ago a
lot of these videos on instagram didn't
have more than 50 views
now i'm breaking the hundreds of views
right now and even getting into the
thousands at least once or twice a week
because i'm honing in more and more on
the exact topics and the exact way to
talk to my target customer
to help them
find those goals now here's another
little trick for you
of what to say in your social media
content here's the kind of the last
point in this podcast episode you're
going to love this
this is why i love tick tock
whatever topic it is that you make
content on
tick tock has a search engine for
course creators
struggling course creators
you can literally go on tick tock
let me have it on the screen i'm telling
you this is how you're going to come up
with some great video content
you type in whatever your topic is once
you figure out those topics
struggling course creators literally
some of my best videos come this way
and you look at
the top videos for that search term
and you watch
how did they make their content
what did they say
okay
and so you're able to literally
look at some of the top videos related
to the topic
that you're
wanting to make make content on but now
here's the cool thing
the tick tock app takes it to an even
better level
okay
i'm actually going to edit this into the
video right here i'm going to press
record on my phone and i'm going to show
you this on the tick tock app
watch this
this is like
going to blow your mind
okay so
you go to
search right here
type in coaching business okay
there's filters in the upper corner
and you can
filter videos that were just posted
this week
to find some of the most relevant
up-to-date videos
about the topics you searched for
you can sort by most like now sometimes
when you sort by most liked they don't
have anything to do with your topic so
just be aware of that
how to actually do
self-care but did you know that most
people are actually doing self-care
wrong okay so there's this thing called
five love languages and so it talks
about the love languages that you can
use with your oh that's incredible your
love language and then also your love
language of your partner so the thing i
wanna
so
that gave me an idea now just that video
right there top video i need to because
i talk about self-care for coaches and
trainers
i should totally make my own take on how
the love languages connect with
self-care you know like well aren't you
copying that girl's idea
yeah
and
it works
i'm not saying word for word the things
she's saying i'm giving my own two cents
based off of that topic so then i do my
own research
and i come up with it on my own i would
not suggest just word for word copying
any of these videos okay
please
hear me out i'm not suggesting that at
all
you use it as inspiration
as a template to give you ideas when
you're struggling to come up with ideas
so some days when i'm just too tired to
come up with ideas i go over to tick
tock and i do a search like that
one of my top videos this past week
was all about a topic
that i pulled from that
a different take on agitating your your
prospects that actually worked really
well over on instagram
right here it popped over over the
thousands
a different take on agitating your
prospects
the algorithm gives you more views based
on how many people are watching all the
way through your video so you know
that a video is doing well instagram is
a good basis on that
has better analytics than tick tock
and i kind of go based off of instagram
because i think it's better for coaches
and trainers
you're able to look at those analytics
and i'm able to see okay that topic
connected with people better and so i
got that topic from watching a video i
actually disagreed with the video that i
watched so i gave my opposite take on
the video that i saw
and that gave me an idea
of what to talk about
in my video content so i hope that this
has given you some really great insight
on ways that you can come up with ideas
to connect with your customer go through
watch through some of my video content
that's going to give you some great
ideas
on how i use
videos as a coach as a trainer
as well there's two pages i want you to
follow
[Music]
brock
johnson brock 11 johnson
on instagram
and how he does video content
he literally teaches you how to make
organic instagram video content okay so
like he's actually way better at this
than i am
check them out okay
and then on tick tock
i want you to go check out
rachel peterson
the mrs peterson she is the queen of
tick tock content way better than i am
at making tick tock content
and watch how they make their content
okay so watch my content watch rachel
peterson's and watch brock johnson's
rachel peterson for tech talk i prefer
her over there and i prefer
brock johnson for instagram because
they're kind of
experts in their own way on those two
platforms they're a little bit different
okay
and that's going to give you a really
cool baseline
for
what to share
who to connect with by the way give me a
shout out if you're watching their
content be like i'm here because of
jeremy crack and tag me in their content
okay
let them know that i'm letting people
know about them
and you're going to learn you're going
to be able to connect with and you're
the dots of
how you talk to your target customer and
how you make really good videos on
social media alright everybody
so listen
if this has helped you
share this episode with somebody
check out some of the courses on my
website
if you want to work with me some
one-on-one coaching
head on over to my website jeremiah.com
schedule a free 45-minute discovery call
with me if you want one-on-one coaching
we can talk about that again my coaching
it's going to start out on june 1st in
just a couple of days
ten thousand dollars
yeah
just a couple days after this podcast
actually released i'm raising the price
to 10 grand
so the monthly payments will be uh
what's 10 grand i think it's like 1 67
for six months 12 sessions of zoom
coaching we can work together one-on-one
to help you grow your business if you
want to try all of jasper it's over at
my website right here as well at the top
here to try out jasper and i'll put it
in the description of this episode so
talk soon everybody grow your life have
a good one